A Finding Aid to the Elizabeth McCausland Papers, 1838-1995, bulk 1920-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.mccaeliz
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1923-1960; Series 2; 2.9 Linear feet Boxes 2-5
  General correspondence is arranged in rough chronological order. Within individual yearly files, McCausland often grouped together letters to and from a particular correspondent; this existing organization has for the most part been maintained. Selected artist correspondence and family correspondence are arranged in files at the end of the series. Correspondence can also be found amongst research and writing files.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  List of Notable Correspondents from Series 2: Correspondence
  List represents only a selection of correspondents from general correspondence.
  A. A. Wynn Inc.: 1951
  ACA Gallery: 1941, 1943, 1945, 1946, 1947
  Abbot, Mary Squire (McIntosh and Otis Company): 1941, 1945, 1947, 1948, 1949, 1950, 1952, 1953, 1954, 1955, 1958
  Abbott, Berenice: 1934
  Adams, Charles: 1938, 1939, 1940, 1943, 1944, 1946, 1947, 1948, 1949, 1950, 1951, 1952
  Adams, Harriet Dyer: 1946
  Adelphi College: 1953
  Adlow, Dorothy ( Christian Science Monitor): 1950, 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954
  Albany Institute of History and Art: 1946, 1947
  Aldrich, Adolf: 1945
  American Academy of Arts and Sciences: 1946, 1947
  American Artist Magazine: 1952
  American Artists Congress: 1938, 1939, 1942
  American Artists Group: 1939, 1945, 1946, 1947, 1950
  American Association of University Women: 1951
  American Federation of Arts: 1946, 1947, 1948, 1949, 1951, 1952, 1954, 1956
  American Museum of Natural History: 1944
  American Newspaper Guild: 1942
  American Philosophical Society: 1947
  Anderson, Mrs. Sherwood (Eleanor): 1949
  Antiques: 1955
  Arden, Elizabeth: 1937
  Arnason, H. Harvard (Walker Art Center): 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954
  Art Digest: 1951
  Art in America (see also Jean Lipman): 1957
  Art Institute of Chicago: 1945, 1947
  Art of this Century: 1944
  Artists for Victory: 1944
  Artists Equity Association: 1956
  Artists League of America: 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945
  Artists Society for National Defense: 1941
  Associated American Artists: 1940
  Baltimore Museum of Art: 1953
  Bard College: 1953
  Barnes, Djuna: 1951
  Barr, Alfred H.: 1939, 1944, 1947, 1951
  Barr, Norman: 1941, 1942, 1943, 1945
  Baumann, Gustave: 1946
  Baur, John I. H.: 1939, 1942, 1946
  Beam, Lura: 1945, 1958
  Beard, Mary: 1938, 1939, 1944
  Benn, Ben: 1951
  Bennington School of the Arts: 1940
  Berkshire Museum: 1939, 1940
  Biddle, George: 1947
  The Bobbs-Merrill Company: 1944
  Bourke-White, Margaret (letter to Berenice Abbott): 1940
  Brewster, William F.: 1954, 1955
  The Brooklyn Museum: 1943, 1945, 1948, 1954
  Brown, Milton: 1945
  Buchholz Gallery: 1941, 1943
  Butler, Joseph (Butler Institute of Art): 1954, 1955
  Cahill, Holger: 1937, 1942, 1944, 1946, 1950
  Carter, Clarence H.: 1945, 1946
  Cinema: 1947
  Clarke, Bert: 1950
  Constantine, Mildred: 1939, 1941, 1942
  Cook, Waldo Leland: 1949
  Cooper Union: 1949, 1952
  Cooper Union Art School: 1947, 1948
  Corcoran Gallery of Art: 1948, 1949, 1950, 1951
  Cowdrey, Mary Bartlett (Smith College Museum of Art): 1943, 1949, 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954
  Crawley, Lawrence: 1950
  Crehan, Hubert ( Art Digest): 1953
  Crichlow, Ernest: 1941
  Curran, Charles: 1942
  D'Harnoncourt, Rene: 1947
  Daura, Pierre: 1949, 1951, 1954
  Detroit Institute of Arts: 1945
  Devree, Howard: 1949
  Diamond (Rotkin), Adele: 1941
  Donato, Louis: 1939
  Dows, Olin: 1942
  Eames, Charles: 1950, 1951
  Estler, William C.: 1944
  Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors: 1946
  Fitch, George: 1955
  Fitch, James: 1940
  Fortune Magazine: 1946
  Francis, Robert: 1940, 1942, 1943
  Frick Art Reference Library: 1944, 1948, 1950, 1951, 1953, 1958
  Friedman, William: 1939
  Fuerstenberg, Eugenia Maurer: 1950, 1951
  Fulton, W. Joseph (University of Chicago): 1951, 1952, 1954, 1955, 1956, 1958, 1959
  G. P. Putnam's Sons: 1937
  Genauer, Emily: 1947
  George Walter Vincent Art Museum (Cordelia Sargent Pond): 1945, 1946, 1947, 1948
  Gibran, Khalil: 1928
  Gilbert, Dorothy: 1950
  Godsoe, Robert Ulrich: 1951
  Golden, Samuel (see also American Artists Group): 1946
  Goodrich, Lloyd: 1942, 1947, 1950, 1951, 1952
  Goodwin, Phillip L.: 1943
  Gottlieb, Harry: 1944
  Griffin, Maude: 1953
  Graham, Martha: 1934, 1942
  Grossman, Sid: 1938
  Gwathmey, Robert: 1945
  Harcourt, Brace and Company: 1947, 1949
  Harper and Brothers: 1951
  Hayes, Bartlett (Addison Gallery of Art): 1942, 1945, 1947
  Hess, Thomas ( Art News): 1950
  Hope, Henry (University of Indiana): 1949, 1950
  International Fine Arts Council: 1950
  Irvine, Rosalind: 1952
  J. B. Lippincott Company: 1951, 1952
  Jacques Seligmann and Company: 1938
  James, Rebecca Salsbury: 1951
  Javitz, Romana: 1946, 1950, 1951, 1952, 1954, 1955
  Jewell, Edward Alden: 1946, 1947
  John Day Company: 1950, 1951, 1955
  John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation: 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945, 1946, 1947, 1952, 1953
  Jones, Howard Mumford (Harvard University): 1947
  Kauffer, E. McKnight: 1946
  Kent, Rockwell: 1945, 1946
  Kirstein, Lincoln: 1941, 1943, 1944, 1946, 1947
  Kish, Maurice: 1945
  Kistler, Aline: 1941
  Knight Publishers Inc.: 1938
  Kuniyoshi, Yasuo: 1945
  Landon, Edward: 1939
  Lange, Dorothea: 1945
  Larkin, Oliver: 1943, 1944, 1949
  Leeper, John and Blanche (see also Corcoran Gallery of Art): 1950, 1951, 1954
  Leighton, George: 1945
  Lerner, Abe (see also World Publishing Company): 1950, 1951
  Lipman, Jean: 1945, 1946, 1947, 1952
  Lipton, Norman C. ( Good Photography): 1941, 1942, 1943
  Longman, Lester: 1940
  MacMahon, Audrey (see also Parnassus): 1936, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1942
  The MacMillan Company: 1943, 1947, 1949, 1950
  Magazine of Art: 1944, 1945, 1946, 1947
  Magriel, Paul: 1954
  Maurer, Alfred L.: 1951
  Metropolitan Museum of Art: 1943, 1947, 1955
  Miller, Dorothy: 1950, 1951
  Milwaukee Art Institute: 1948
  Minicam Photography: 1941, 1943, 1944
  Modernage Furniture Corp.: 1945
  More, Herman (Whitney Museum of American Art): 1954
  Morton, Phillip: 1951, 1952
  Mount Holyoke College: 1943
  Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute: 1956
  Museum of Modern Art: 1934, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945
  Museum of the City of New York: 1958
  N.W. Ayer and Son: 1945, 1946, 1950
  The Nation: 1940, 1955
  National Gallery of Art: 1944, 1945
  National Maritime Union: 1945
  Navas, Elizabeth: 1952, 1953, 1954
  Neuberger, Roy: 1952
  The New American Library: 1955, 1956
  The New Republic: 1944, 1947
  The New School for Social Research: 1945
  The New York Herald Tribune: 1945, 1947
  New York Historical Society: 1943
  New York Public Library: 1943, 1955, 1956
  New York State Museum: 1949
  The New York Times: 1940
  Newark Museum: 1944
  Newhall, Beaumont: 1944
  Newhall, Nancy: 1945
  Norman, Dorothy: 1934, 1937, 1938, 1940
  Old Print Shop: 1945
  Olmsted, Anna Wetherill (Syracuse Museum of Art): 1950
  Opportunity: 1943, 1944, 1945
  Ossorio, Alfonso: 1953
  P. F. Collier and Son Corp.: 1947, 1948, 1949, 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954, 1955, 1957, 1958
  Pach, Walter: 1955
  Parnassus: 1939
  Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Art: 1951
  Pepsi-Cola Company: 1944, 1945
  Philadelphia Art Alliance: 1946
  Pierre Matisse Gallery: 1938, 1939
  Popular Photography: 1943
  Portland Art Museum: 1940
  Porter, Eliot: 1954
  Printer's Ink (Carl Weiss): 1951
  Railway Express Agency: 1949
  Rivera, Diego: 1949
  Rogers, John C.: 1941
  Roosevelt, Eleanor: 1944
  Rosenblum, Walter: 1944
  Rothschild, Lincoln: 1937, 1942, 1945, 1946, 1949
  Royce, William: 1933, 1934, 1935, 1942, 1958
  Rukeyser, Muriel: 1941, 1950
  San Francisco Chronicle: 1951, 1953
  Sarah Lawrence College: 1942, 1943, 1944
  Saturday Evening Post: 1946
  Schlesinger, Arthur: 1943
  School Art League of New York City: 1953, 1954
  Schwimmer, Rosika: 1933, 1935, 1943
  Sculpture's Guild: 1938, 1940, 1941
  Segy, Ladislaw: 1943
  Shelter: 1939
  Sloan, John: 1951
  Smith College Museum of Art: 1939, 1954
  Soby, James Thrall: 1935, 1946, 1951
  Social Science Research Council: 1948
  Springfield Museum of Fine Art: 1938, 1940, 1941
  Standard Oil: 1946
  Stein, Gertrude: 1934
  Sterling, Charles (Department of Painting, The Louvre): 1951
  Strand, Paul: 1942
  Survey Associates: 1938, 1939
  Sweeney, James John: 1954, 1955, 1956
  Thornton, Russell (see also Corcoran Gallery of Art): 1951, 1952, 1953
  Time Magazine: 1945
  Toklas, Alice B.: 1949
  Traphagen School of Fashion: 1957
  U.S. Camera: 1940
  University of Chicago Library: 1951
  University of Minnesota: 1951
  University of Nebraska: 1953, 1954, 1956, 1957
  Vanderbilt, Paul (Library of Congress): 1950
  Vogue Magazine: 1953
  Vose, Robert C.: 1945
  Wade, Henry: 1954
  Walker Art Center: 1946, 1947, 1949, 1950, 1951
  Walker, Hudson: 1948, 1949, 1950, 1951, 1952
  Ward, Lynd: 1942, 1945, 1947
  Western Photography: 1946
  Weston, Edward: 1943
  Weyhe Gallery: 1940, 1951
  Wheaton College: 1955
  Wheeler, Monroe: 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945
  Whitney Museum of American Art: 1946, 1947, 1951
  Wichita Art Association: 1947
  Williams, Hermann Warner (see also Corcoran Gallery of Art): 1950, 1951, 1952, 1954
  Wilson, Sol: 1945
  Worcester Art Museum: 1943, 1945
  World Publishing Company: 1946, 1949, 1950, 1955
  Yale University Art Gallery: 1949
  Yale University Library: 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954
  Young, Art: 1941
  Young Artists Guild: 1948
  - General Correspondence, 1923-1927 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - General Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - General Correspondence, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - General Correspondence, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - General Correspondence, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 36-39)
  - General Correspondence, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
  - General Correspondence, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 42-47)
  - General Correspondence, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 6-11)
  - General Correspondence, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 12-21)
  - General Correspondence, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 22-33)
  - General Correspondence, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 34-41)
  - General Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 42-45)
  - General Correspondence, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - General Correspondence, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8-17)
  - General Correspondence, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 18-27)
  - General Correspondence, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 28-32)
  - General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 33-37)
  - General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 38-41)
  - General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, circa 1923-1960 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Artist Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Dove, Arthur, 1933-1938 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - Eilshemius, Louis, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Enters, Angna, 1928-1935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, [1933]-1935 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1931-1938 (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
    - Various, 1937-1943 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Includes letters from Alexander Calder, Howard Cook, Alice Decker, Rockwell Kent, Fernando Puma, Moses Soyer, Sylvia Wald, and Art Young.
  - Family Correspondence (Letters to Belle Noble McCausland), 1927-1935, 1943, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 21-23)
- General Writings, circa 1930-1954; Series 3; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  This series comprises some of McCausland's general writings apart from those related to specific research projects, including speeches and lectures, poems, and scattered essays and articles. Speeches and lectures include ones on art criticism and patronage, on the artist Marsden Hartley, and on various art topics given at various universities, conferences, meetings, and other events from 1940 to the mid-1950s. Poems most likely date from the 1930s and include manuscripts of individual poems and titled collections, which McCausland may have published on her own private press. Also found are some unpublished manuscripts, including two "dummy" articles written for a proposed magazine at the request of Bob Rogers and some material relating to a proposed book on silk screen, and a manuscript of an article on scientific photography by Willard D. Morgan, which may have been ghostwritten by McCausland.
  General writings are arranged alphabetically. Related material can be found amongst research and writing files and correspondence.
  - "The Effect of Art on Freedom of Expression", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Essays and Speeches on Art Criticism, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
  - Essays and Speeches on Patronage, 1945-1953 (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
  - Ghostwriting, circa 1930-1954 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1946 (Box 5, Folder 31-32)
  - On the "Blue Menace", 1928 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Poems, early 1930s-1950 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
  - Poems, Manuscripts (Box 5)
    - No Returning (1), circa 1930-1954 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Jungle (2), circa 1930-1954 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Autumn Interlude (3), circa 1930-1954 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Return to Life (4), circa 1930-1954 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - From September, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "The Return of the Native" (Lecture on Marsden Hartley), 1952 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - "Roots of American Art," Drafts, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 42-44)
  - Speeches, Manuscripts, 1938-1940, undated (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
  - Speeches, Manuscripts, 1945-1948 (Box 5, Folder 47-49)
  - Speeches, Notecards, 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 50-52)
  - Speeches, Notecards, circa 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Speeches, Notecards, 1952-1954 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1935-1947 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - "Windward Feather", 1927 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1930-1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Alfred H. Maurer, bulk 1948-1950; 1851-1951; Series 4; 3.7 Linear feet Boxes 6-9
  Series consists of files relating to McCausland's research for the exhibition, "A. H. Maurer: 1868-1932" (Walker Art Center, September 11-October 16, 1949 and Whitney Museum of American Art, November 6-December 11, 1949), which she helped organize and for which she did the catalog, and her book, A. H. Maurer, which was published for the Walker Art Center by A. A. Wyn in 1951. Files consist of correspondence, drafts and manuscripts of the exhibition catalog and book, and extensive research material, including photographs of Maurer's paintings (organized according either to the year they were executed and to their subject matter), photographs of the artist, notes on his life and work (typically organized according to time period or period of execution), notes on his correspondence, and other material. Also found is some Maurer art work.
  Correspondence consists of incoming and copies of outgoing letters. Correspondents include Walker Art Center staff, friends and family of Maurer contacted as part of McCausland's research (his sister Eugenia Maurer Fuerstenberg and his nephew Alfred S. Maurer, and former friends Fra Dana, Pierre Daura, Georgia O'Keeffe, and Grace Phillips, among others), publishers, museums, research institutions, and other instrumental figures, such as Hudson Walker and Lloyd Goodrich. The contents of many correspondence files are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  The largest portion of the Maurer files are devoted to photographs of his paintings (not scanned). These seem to have been collected as part of an effort to record "about a thousand Maurers," which were photographed in small batches of four or six at a time. These photographs were then used, in conjunction with available documentation, to date Maurer's works based on style, and have not been scanned. Other photographs used in the research seem to have been copied from Maurer's friends and family members.
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  The series has been partially scanned. Photographs of works of art have not been scanned.
  - A. H. Maurer (Box 6)
    - First Draft, pp. 1-35, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - First Draft, pp. 36-95, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - First Draft, pp. 96-174, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    - First Draft, pp. 175-appendix, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
    - Foreword, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Prologue, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 1, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 2, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 3, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 4, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 5, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 6, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 7, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 8, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Epilogue, Draft, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Footnotes, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Notes, Front of Book, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Notes, Corrections, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Proofs and Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Art Work (Box 6)
    - Linoleum Cut Prints, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Linoleum Cut Prints (Exhibition Announcements), 1927-1928 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Linoleum Cut on Broadside by Sherwood Anderson, circa 1900-1951 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Tempera Sketches, circa 1900-1951 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Watercolor Sketch, circa 1900-1951 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Captions for Illustrations, circa 1949 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Catalog Essay (Box 6)
    - Notes, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - First Draft, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Second Draft, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Third Draft, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Clippings on Maurer, 1924, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Copies of Maurer's Medical Records (See also General and Medical Research), circa 1948 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Copy for Catalog with Letters and Memos, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 45-47)
  - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - A-C, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Catalog, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 49-50)
    - D, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Dana, Fra, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Defenbacher, Dan (Walker Art Center), 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 53-54)
    - E, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Friedman, William (Walker Art Center), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Fuerstenberg, Eugenia Maurer, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 57-58)
    - G, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Geske, Norman A. (Walker Art Center), 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - H, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - L-M, 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Maurer Letters in Gertrude Stein Collection at Yale University, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      Includes some correspondence with Alice B. Toklas.
    - N, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - P, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Phillips, Grace A., 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Photographs, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - R-T, 1931, 1948-1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Includes letter to Maurer from Jack Gage Stark dated 1931.
    - U-V, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - W, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Walker, Hudson, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence with Lloyd Goodrich regarding the manuscript for the Maurer biography.
    - Y-Z, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 1948-1953 (Box 7, Folder 7-10)
  - Correspondence and Notes, "Leads", 1945, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Correspondence, and Clippings (from Eugenia Maurer Fuerstenberg), 1910-1937 (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - Expenses, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Foreword to Maurer Catalog for Buchholz Gallery Exhibition, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - General and Medical Research, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Interviews, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 17-20)
  - Invitation List, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Maurer, Louis, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Maurers in the Stieglitz Collection, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Notes (Box 7)
    - Notes, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 24-26)
    - Notes, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Esthetics, 1921, 1928, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - New York Public Library, circa 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Paintings, Executed 1890-1940, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - "Flowers," circa 1912, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Photographs, Personal (Box 7)
    - Maurer, Louis, circa 1920-1951 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Memorabilia, circa 1920-1951 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Paris, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Portraits, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Shady Brook, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 37-38)
    - Studio, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Portraits by Other Artists, circa 1920-1951 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Photographs, Unsorted, [1948] (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Photographs of Paintings, [1948] (Box 7, Folder 42-50)
  - Photographs of Paintings (Box 7)
    - Executed 1890-1900, [1948-1949] (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Executed 1890-circa 1908, [1948-1949] (Box 7, Folder 52-53)
    - Executed 1901-1902, [1948-1949] (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Executed 1903-1904, [1948-1949] (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Executed 1905, [1948-1949] (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Executed circa 1908-1909, [1948-1949] (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Executed 1915-1919, [1948-1949] (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Executed circa 1920, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Executed 1920-1921, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Executed 1921-1923, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Executed ante 1924, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Executed 1924, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Executed 1925, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
    - Executed 1926, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Executed 1927, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Executed circa 1927-1928, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - Executed 1928-1929, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Executed 1930, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Executed 1930-1932, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Unknown Execution, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Abstract Heads, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Double Paintings", [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Flowers, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
    - Flowers, unknown execution, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Heads, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 21-24)
    - Heads, Early, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 25-27)
    - Heads, Early (Duplicates for Bertha Schaeffer), 1948 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Landscapes, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 29-32)
    - Miscellaneous, [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 33-35)
    - "Paris", [1948-1949] (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - [Prints for Illustrations?], [1948-1949] (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Self-Portrait, Executed circa 1904, [1948-1949] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Sports", [1948-1949] (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Still Lifes, [1948-1949] (Box 9, Folder 4-9)
    - "Technical Appendix", [1948-1949] (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Two Girls, [1948-1949] (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Two Heads, [1948-1949] (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - "The Wrestlers", 1949 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Paintings File, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 14-16)
  - Photographs of Paintings File (Box 9)
    - Correspondence and Notes, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
    - Correx and Notes, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
    - List of Works by Louis Maurer, circa 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Self-Portrait, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Self-Portrait (owned by Paul Shaskan), 1943, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Prints and Drawings, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 24)